Maria Brock

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(270) 792-7800 | mariabrock414@gmail.com

github.com/mariabrock

www.linkedin.com/in/maria-brock

www.mariabrock.dev

About

My interest in web development sparked while still in a high school technology course. One of our class projects was to make a basic website for a newly branded coffee shop. I don't remember the name, or brand, but I remember that I was proud of that project. I was intrigued by this thing known as "coding" but didn't initially consider it a career path. I went on to college and graduated as a graphic designer where I have freelanced in many areas over the years. Alongside design, I gained valuable experience in the customer service space. I had a friend recommend that I take a look at Nashville Software School and what I found reignited my interest in web development. Now my love for tech and all things design, has excited me to leverage both my design and coding skills in the ever evolving world of technology.

Projects

IMAGINE OUT LOUD

Imagine Out Loud is an app built to encourage families to read aloud together while spending quality time together and staying away from excessive screen time. Reading aloud is critical in early childhood development and helps in language, speech and literacy. My application is designed for use by a parent, or an older child who will track books being read and the amount of time that is read aloud.

- Built in React, JavaScript, CSS and HTML
- Utilizes Firebase, and Google Auth for user login
- User is able to add to and delete from their collection
- Can add or edit a time they recorded
- allows visual for working toward a screen free time goal

View Project

github.com/mariabrock/read-aloud-tracker

Education

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Full Stack Software Developement

WESTERN KENTUCKY UNIVERSITY

BA in Graphic Design

FLORIDA COLLEGE

AA in Liberal Studies

Experience

NASHVILLE SOFTWARE SCHOOL

Software Engineer

Full year part-time software development bootcamp focusing on full-stack development fundamentals, problem solving and working in an Agile evironment.

- Source code version control with Git/GitHub
- Project planning/tracking with Github Projects & Issue Tracking
- JavaScript fundamentals including modular, readable code and reusable components
- Built single-page applications with HTML, CSS, and JavaScript libraries like jQuery
- Built full CRUD applications using ReactJs framework
- Database/API utilizing Firebase, JSON, promises, and axios calls
- C# & ASP.NET fundamentals, along with databases utilizing SQL, ADO, and Dapper
- Styled applications with CSS Frameworks Bootstrap and wrote custom styles with SASS

Group Project: Nutshell - Star Destroyer

Use this application to view the Star Destroyer Database and its contents. When logged in as a member of the Galactic Empire, via Google Authentication, you can modify the Star Destroyer's database contents using CRUD components on each page.

- Nutshell-Star Destroyer is built in JavaScript, CSS and HTML.
- github.com/nss-evening-cohort-10/nutshell-star-destroyer

WEX, INC

2019 to Present

2019 to Present

Vendor Enablement Specialist

Customer support position where I facilitated communication between clients and internal call team to onboard client vendors into an online credit card payment process.

- Assist, coordinate, and execute direct mail, email, and telephone enrollment campaigns
- Monitor and analyze campaigns and perform analysis; providing recap, summary, and pertinent reporting on results and next steps
 - Microsoft Suite, GSuite, and an Internal Software called Wexlp/ACOM
- Facilitate changes and updates in the database to maintain client data integrity within databases
- Lead weekly update calls and maintain a positive relationship with clients before, throughout the campaign process
- Measure weekly coordination metrics and deliver results

FANTASTIK INK

2008 to Present

Freelance Graphic Designer

Acquired projects by personal references and word of mouth. Projects ranged from basic copy and paste image replacements to larger print campaigns

- Designed logos, print materials, and web graphics for small intimate print campaigns (ex: Sacred Selections Bowling Green)
- Produced designs from concept to completion using Adobe Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator
- Have developed guides and mood boards that include fonts, colors, and logo variations used in developing cohesive brands

BELK

Retail Associate

• Maintained and prioritized a positive and comprehensive customer experience

- Responsible for maintaining and setting displays via corporate standards
- Performed daily opening/closing procedures, handled cash and accurately reported earnings

JIMMY JOHNS

2013 to 2017

2017 to 2019

Assistant Manager

- Worked in a close team environment to problem solve and deliver quality to our customers.
- Worked to provide leadership within that team environment to ensure standards are maintained and exceeded.
- Responsible for timely and accurate execution of store policies/procedures